Pablo Esquerdo Roig

Junior Software Engineer (interested in Data Science/Machine Learning)

Eindhoven, Netherlands (willing to relocate)

E-mail: pabloesquerdo@gmail.com - Phone: +31 0630074874

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-esquerdo-roig-482bba12b/ Blog: https://anintelligentfool.github.io

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a junior software engineer who is really interested in starting a professional career as a Data Scientist/ Machine Learning. I have practical knowledge about this field from attending different on-line courses using Python, a personal project for stock predictor (still working on it). Regarding my previous jobs, I have participated in different projects and roles where I have acquired experience in C#, Scrum Master, Communication skills, Business Intelligence. Furthermore, I love to learn new technologies and programming technics in order to improve my skills and keep me up to date. I consider myself a hardworking person who thinks every goal is possible with effort and sacrifice and not afraid to changes. I have proven to be creative, proactive and flexible.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer BDO January 2019 – Present (Eindhoven)

- Development and customization of a web page.
- o ASP.NET using MVC pattern for the back-end.
- TypeScript, React and JavaScript for the front-end.
- o Microsoft SQL Server.
- Using SCRUM as an agile development methodology.
- Using Git as a code review and Nuget as a continuous Integration processes.

Software Developer G2Speech March 2018 – December 2018 (Eindhoven)

- Development of improvements of a desktop application based on the client expectations.
- Adding functionality to an existing application.
- o C# and .NET on Microsoft Visual Studio 2017.
- o Microsoft SQL Server.
- Using a MVVM pattern for the different layers.
- Experience with development practices like SOLID, TDD and Unit Testing.
- Working with WPF and XAML.
- Using SCRUM as an agile development methodology.
- Using Git as a code review and Nuget as a continuous Integration processes
- Using LINQ framework.
- Using Resharper extension for code analysis and refactoring.

Food Seller Vital Ingredient September 2017 – March 2018 (London)

- o Improvement of English Skills.
- o Improvement of Communication Skills.

- Salesman in Carrefour's electronic sector Jun 2016 Aug 2016 (Spain)
 - o Learn all the characteristics of the different products.
 - Explain the costumer the characteristics of products in an understandable, simplified way.
 - o Try to help the customer decide on the best option for each specific customer.
 - Developing good communication and sales skills.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING COURSES

Introduction to Linux (2014), EdX, 84h on-line https://verify.edx.org/cert/57fc150518e04642ab713b7a6d99c8ca Skills: *Linux*

Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Python in Data Science (2019), Udemy, 41.5h on-line

Skills: Scikit-learn, CNN, ANN, clustering, random forest, KNN,Pandas, Numpy, Keras, Matplotlib, Python, Anaconda, Spyder

Data Analysis with Pandas and Python (2019), udemy, 20h on-line

Skills: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, pyplot

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate (2019)- Coursera, 120h on-line

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/DJ67JGCRM8DG

Skills: Scikit-learn, seaborn, pyplot, Database, Clustering, Pandas, Numpy, Jupyter Notebook, IBM Cloud, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Machine Learning

Deep Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Artificial Neural Networks (2019), udemy, 23h on-line

Skills: Scikit-learn, CNN, ANN, RNN, clustering, Boltzmann Machine, AutoEncoder

EDUCATION

BSc in Software Engineer (SEP 2012 – Jul 2017)

University of Alicante – Alicante, Spain 4 years degree (240 ECTS), GPA: 65%

• **Final degree project:** Research and development of a speech recognition system in Matlab using characteristics of the glottal pulse. Design a complete speech recognition system catching every glottal pulse and separating it from background noise, calculating the average of all stimuli and analyzing in temporal domain and spectral domain. With the obtained results, determine the optimal threshold so as to ultimately obtain a program with an effectiveness of 80%.

OTHER INFORMATION

- Languages: English (Professional working proficiency), Spanish (Native), Catalan (Native), Dutch (Basic-Learning)
- Driving License
- Hobbies: travelling, sports, cook, videogames.

Up to date 01/08/2019